

Ruben Caliandro

Technical Artist, Game Programmer, Full-Stack Web Developer

CONTACT

Date of Birth June 7, 1990

Email ruben.caliandro@gmail.com

(+39) 333 736 8333

Location Torino, IT

PROFILES

Github https://github.com/chosko

Linkedin https://www.linkedin.com/in/rubencaliandro/en

http://chosko.com Personal

I have a strong interest in Computer Graphics and Videogames since I was 15.

I work as Techical Artist and Game Programmer at Tiny Bull Studios, an indie game developer based in Torino (Italy).

I make real-time visual effects and I am specialized in writing shaders for Virtual Reality.

ABOUT

I am also Web Developer since 2010. I worked in companies located in Italy (Torino) and USA (Sunnyvale, CA).

I graduated with a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science in 2012 and a Master's degree in Virtual Reality in 2017, both of them with the maximum score of 110/100 with honors.

WORK EXPERIENCE

♥ TURIN, ITALY

m Dec, 2016 - PRESENT

O 1 YEAR 7 MONTHS

Technical Artist, Game Programmer at Tiny Bull Studios srl: (http://www.tinybullstudios.com/)

Visual Effects and Game Programming

- Shader Programming
- Particle Systems and Post-Processing
- Game Programming and Optimization
- Making the effects support Virtual Reality
- Main Technologies: Unity, C#, ShaderLab, CG/HLSL/GLSL, Oculus, Vive, PlayStation s4

♥ TURIN, ITALY MAY, 2015 - SEP, 2017 O 2 YEARS 5 MONTHS Full-stack Web Developer at Tandù srl: (http://tandu.it)

Project Management and Full-Stack Development.

- Main technologies: Node.js/Express, Ruby on Rails, AngularJS, AWS ElasticBeanstalk, Docker, CircleCI

SUNNYVALE, CA. USA O 3 MONTHS Front-end Web Developer at Eversnap: (http://www.geteversnap.com/home.html)

Front-end Development

- Web application development (front-end) using AngularIS
- Project architecture refactoring
- Automatic tools and CI with git, GruntIS and Fabric
- Development process used: Scrum

♥ TURIN, ITALY # JAN, 2013 - JAN, 2014

O 1 YEAR

Web Application Developer at MyTable:

Full-Stack Development

- Web Application Design and Development (both Client and Server-Side).
- Design and Development of some Ruby Gems (and Rails Engines).
- Skills: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, MySQL, UML

♥ TURIN, ITALY O 2 YEARS 10 MONTHS Web Application Developer at Condominioitalia Editrice:

Web Development

- Web Application Design, Developement and Graphics.
- Recording and Editing of the online news 'TG del Condominio'.
- Skills: PHP, MySQL, (X)HTML, Javascript.

Volunteer

Film Projectionist, Cinema Teatro Cuore:

O 3 YEARS 9 MONTHS

- Film assembling and deassembling.
- Security checks.

35mm Film Projections

- Website maintenance.
- Film projections with manual changeovers, using two Cinemeccanica Victoria 8.

EDUCATION

EXPECTED SCORE: 110/110

Università degli studi di Torino - Computer Science Department Master of Science: Computer Graphics, Virtual Reality and Multimedia

- MFN0978 - Virtual Reality Systems - 30/30 with honors - MFN0947 - Multimedia Database - 28/30

- MFN0972 - Digital Image Processing and Artificial Vision - 30/30

- MFN0970 - Physics for Virtual Reality - 30/30 - MFN0942 - Artificial Intelligence - 30/30

- MFN0973 - 3D Graphics Modeling - 30/30 with honors - MFN0962 - Numerical Methods - 20/30

- MFN0960 - Concurrent Models and Distributed Algorithms - 30/30

- MFN0963 - English II - Approved - MFN0961 - Information Theory - 27/30

- MFN0949 - Cognitive Systems - 30/30

- MFN0951 - Digital Audio and Music Processing - 30/30 with honors - MFN0977 - Neural Networks - 30/30

Thesis: Visual Effects for Real-Time Stereoscopic Rendering

Università degli studi di Torino - Computer Science Department Bachelor of Science: Computer Science (Networks) Score: 110/110 WITH Thesis: Spam Analysis tools High School P. Gobetti High School: Science Thesis: Mathematics applied to 3D Computer Graphics Programming PROJECTS Blind (https://www.tinybullstudios.com/games/blind/) — VR Game Blind is a narrative-driven psychological thriller for virtual reality where the player is blind and must explore their surroundings □ Dec, 2016 — Present using echolocation. - Keywords: Virtual Reality, Puzzle Game, Unity, Oculus, SteamVR, PlayStation VR Feed The Troll (https://risingpixel.itch.io/feed-the-troll) — Videogame **SEP. 2016** Feed the Troll has been developed in 48h during the MTV Mega Game Jam @ MTV Digital Days 2016. It is a multi-player multi-device $videogame, with an unconventional\ game play\ based\ on\ real\ communication\ between\ the\ players.$ - Winner of the MTV Mega Game Jam 2016 - Keywords: 2D Game, Asymmetrical co-op multiplayer, Unity $\textbf{Tron Lightcycles} \ (\text{https://github.com/chosko/lightcycle}) \ -- \ 3D \ Model$ **⊞** DEC, 2014 A 3D scene representing two Lightcycles from the movie 'Tron Legacy'. Modeled with Blender, with shaders programmed in OSL. - Keywords: 3D Modeling, Blender, Shaders, OSL $\textbf{Lazy} \, (\texttt{http://www.chosko.com/en/video_games/lazy.html}) \, - \, \textbf{Videogame}$ ₩ FEB, 2015 Lazy is the video game who doesn't want to be played. Starting from the main menu, everything seems like the game is not willing to play with you, and he will try everything to make you exit. - Keywords: 3D Game, First Person, Unity3D, Cross-Platform $hosko.com/en/video_games/battlebugs.html#content-top)$ — Videogame Aug, 2014 Battle Bugs has been developed by the team in 48h for the Alpha Game Jam, in San Francisco. The goal of this strategy game is to defend your home hive and destroy the enemy hive, or defeat all the enemy bugs - Keywords: 2D Game, Strategy, Unity3D, Cross-Platform $\textbf{ScrollCraft} \ (\text{http://www.windowsphone.com/it-it/store/app/scrollcraft/8f7c61d3-9f2b-4092-b02d-212519f872d8}) \\ - \ \textbf{Videogame} \ (\text{http://www.windowsphone.com/it-it/store/app/scrollcraft/8f7c61d3-b02d-212519f872d8}) \\ - \ \textbf{Videogame} \ (\text{http://www.$ ₩ Nov, 2013 Developed in 48hours, during the international Indie Speed Run 2013. It is an endless runner featuring the theme and the element assigned to the team: Speed and Scroll. - Keywords: 2D Game, MonoGame, C#, Cross-Platform - Team members: Roberto Pesando, Stefano Nada, Stefano Ordine and I AMCG (https://github.com/psicomante/aamcg) — Videogame ∰ JUL, 2013 Another Multiplayer Cuboids Game: a shared-screen party game where characters are controlled with smartphones. - Keywords: Unity, C#, GLSL, Network, Multiplayer - Team members: Roberto Pesando and I $\textbf{Minesweeper3D} \ (\text{https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/8771146/Minesweeper3D.zip}) - \textbf{Videogame}$ $A 3D \ version \ of the \ classic \ Minesweeper \ made \ in \ 48h. \ The \ puzzle \ is \ really \ hard \ to \ solve: \ the \ average \ resolution \ time \ for \ a \ 10x10x15$ grid is about an hour. - Keywords: 3D Game, Puzzle Game, XNA, C# Continuum (https://github.com/xteamdimension/continuum-arena) — Videogame A 2D space shooter for Windows Phone made with XNA. Collecting "tachyon streams" you are enabled to rewind and warp the time. - Keywords: 2D Game, Space Shooter, XNA, Windows Phone, Time Travel. - Team members: Stefano Nada, Stefano Ordine and I Mathematics applied to 3D Computer-Graphics programming (https://github.com/Chosko/high-school-thesis) = 3D Simulation, High School SchooA 3D Simulation of the Solar System built with C# and DirectX, presented as a thesis demo at the end of the High School - Keywords: 3D Simulation, DirectX, C#, HLSL shaders, High School Thesis MTV Mega Game Jam @ MTV Digital Days 2016 AWARDS Award won with "Feed The Troll", an asymmetrical co-op multiplayer made with Unity WINNER **≅** SEP 10, 2016 Alpha Game Jam 2014, San Francisco Award won with "Battle Bugs", a strategy 2D game made with Unity ₩ Aug 15, 2014 Global Game Jam 2015, Turin Competition THIRD PLACE Award won with "Lazy", the game who doesn't want to be played. Made with Unity **∰** Feb 23, 2015 Italian Native speaker LANGUAGES English Professional working proficiency Guitar: Electric Guitar, Classical Guitar

Interests

Film Projectionism: 35mm film projections

Rubik's Cube: up to 4x4x4